amerisourcebergen.com 2019-12-11

# Privacy Statement

**PLEASE READ AND REVIEW THE FOLLOWING PRIVACY STATEMENT CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS WEBSITE**

This Privacy Statement (“Privacy Statement”) sets forth the privacy policies and practices of AmerisourceBergen Corporation, and its subsidiaries and/or affiliates (collectively, “AmerisourceBergen”), as they relate to the collection, use and disclosure of information in connection with your use of amerisourcebergen.com (“Web Site”). Please read this Privacy Statement carefully and completely before using this Web Site. 

By accessing and using this Web Site after the notification banner or message appears on the Web Site, and any subsequent times thereafter, you expressly agree to the terms of this Privacy Statement and consent to the collection and use of your information as set forth herein. If you do not agree to this Privacy Statement, you are not authorized to access this Web Site or use any of its features and must immediately discontinue use of this Web Site. The terms “we”, “us”, and “our” refer to AmerisourceBergen, and the terms “you” or “yours” refers to you, as user of this Web Site. By accessing and using this Web Site, you also agree to the Terms and Conditions.  

**Collection of Your Information**

The amount and type of information we collect depends on how you use this Web Site.  AmerisourceBergen may collect information about you from a variety of sources, including (a) information you provide directly; (b) information we collect about you when you visit our Web Site, use of our services, or view our online advertisements; and (c) information we receive from other sources.

(a) Information We Collect Directly From You.  We may collect information directly from you when you visit our Web Site, choose to use services or participate in programs or otherwise provide information directly to us.  

Information we collect directly from you includes user ID and password; name, email address, postal address, telephone number; payment details; information about you such as date of birth, gender and other demographic information; product and service preferences and/or behaviors; and future communication preferences.

(b) Information We Collect About You. We may automatically collect information about you when you visit our Web Site, use our services, or view online advertisements. We may log data or use tracking technologies such as cookies and web beacons to collect this information about you. For more information about our use of tracking technologies, see our Cookies and Tracking Technologies Policy (“Cookie Policy”) by visiting our Cookies Policy.  

We may collect the following information about you:

  * Technical information, including your IP address, browser type and version, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and device-specific information, such as time zone setting and mobile network information (including location information); and
  * Information about your visit, including, web pages you view, links you click, language preferences web sites you visited before coming to our Web Site, page response times, download errors, page interaction information (such as lengths of visits to certain pages, scrolling, clicks and mouse-overs), or your destination when you leave the Web Site.

(c) Information We Receive From Other Sources. We work closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers) and may receive information about you from them. Please be advised that any information provided to us by a third party may also be subject to that third party’s Privacy Statement.

**How We Use This Information  
**AmerisourceBergen may use the information we collect to provide you the services and products you request and to tell you about other services and products that may be available to you.  We also use this information to manage and maintain our Web Site.  Specifically, we may use this information as follows:

_Information We Collect Directly From You.    
_We may collect this information for uses that include, but are not limited to:

  * fulfilling our obligations arising from any contracts entered between you and us and providing you with the information, product and service you request;
  * providing you with other services that we have offered to you; 
  * creating and managing your account; 
  * developing and providing advertising tailored to your interests;
  * sending you service-related communications; or
  * ensuring that content from the Web Site is presented in the most effective way for you and your computer.

_Information We Collect About You._  
We may collect this information for uses that include, but are not limited to:

  * administering and improving our Web Site, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * analyzing the use of our products and services;
  * measuring the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you and others; or
  * making suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our Web Site about goods and/or services that may interest you or them.

_Information We Receive From Other Sources_.

We may combine information we receive from other sources (such as our customers,  suppliers, affiliates, public websites, public agencies, market research companies, contractors and consultants) with the information we collect directly from you and information we collect about you. We may use this information and the combined information for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Statement.

**Legal Basis Under EU General Data Protection Regulation for Processing Personal Data of EU Residents**

Where you have consented to data processing, your consent provides the legal basis to process your Personal Data (as defined below). You have the right to withdraw consent at any time. Please note that your withdrawal of consent to collect and process your Personal Data will not affect the lawfulness of processing your Personal Data based on your consent before you withdrew your consent.

We may also process your Personal Data on the basis of contractual necessity to perform a contract we have with you. 

We may also process your Personal Data on the basis of our legitimate interests, including in providing and improving the services. For example, AmerisourceBergen has a legitimate interest in understanding your login history so we can assess your interaction with our services. We also have a legitimate interest in providing and developing interesting features to provide to our users. 

Where we rely on legitimate interests to process your Personal Data, you have the right to object to such processing (meaning that you can ask us to stop). You can use your privacy settings to control certain ways in which we process your Personal Data. You can also contact us, using the details below, to object to other forms of processing.

**Sharing Your Information**

_Sharing Information With Third Parties._  

When you provide Personal Data to AmerisourceBergen we may make it accessible to certain third party service providers to perform a variety of services on our behalf. These service providers include business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you; advertisers and advertising networks for selecting and serving relevant adverts to you and others; and analytics and search engine providers for assisting us in the administration and improvement of the Web Site.  Please note that we provide our service providers with only the Personal Data that is necessary for them to perform services and only for use for such purposes. “Personal Data” means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, where an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

There may also be instances where AmerisourceBergen may share your Personal Data with third-parties who have not been retained by us (directly or indirectly), for example, if we are required to do so because of an applicable law, court order or governmental regulation; if such disclosure is otherwise necessary in support of any criminal or other legal investigation or proceeding here or abroad; in order to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions or other agreements; and to protect the rights, property or safety of AmerisourceBergen or our customers.

Personal Data collected from you may also be transferred to a third party in the event that AmerisourceBergen or a part of it is sold, assigned or transferred, or as part of the process of considering such a transaction, in which case we would use reasonable endeavors to ensure the actual or proposed buyer, assignee or transferee would treat your information in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

_Sharing With AmerisourceBergen Affiliates._  
AmerisourceBergen may share information we collect with AmerisourceBergen subsidiaries and affiliates for the same purposes and under the same legal justifications as are described for AmerisourceBergen under this Privacy Policy. 

**Cookies, Web Beacons and other Technologies**

This Section provides you with additional information on our use of cookies, web beacons and other technologies.

Cookies.  A cookie is a small file placed on your computer when you visit a site that can be understood by the site that issued the cookie. We use cookies to monitor how our Web Site is used and to help personalize your online experience in order to give you the best possible experience on our Web Site.  You can accept or decline cookies. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. For more details, including how you can amend your preferences, please see our Cookie Policy. You may also go to the cookie settings available in your specific web browser to learn more about cookies. Although you are not required to accept cookies or provide AmerisourceBergen information when you visit this Web Site, if you set your browser to reject cookies (or decide not to provide AmerisourceBergen certain information) you may not be able to use all of the features and functionality of this Web Site.

Web Beacons. Web beacons are small bits of code that communicate with third parties and are embedded in web pages, our ads or in e-mails.  We may use web beacons to deliver or communicate with cookies, to count users who have visited a web page or to understand usage patterns or other third-party functionality.  We also may include web beacons in e-mails to learn if messages have been opened, acted on, or forwarded. You can disable the ability of web beacons to store cookie information by declining cookies. Please see our Cookie Policy to learn more about web beacons and how to disable any web beacons.

Other Technologies.  From time to time, we may use other technologies, such as cross-device tracking, to provide better service to you. “Cross-device tracking” associates multiple devices with the same consumer and links a consumer’s activity across her devices (e.g., smartphones, tablets, personal computers, and other connected devices).

**Third-Party Advertising  **

We may use third parties, including ad networks, to display advertising on our Web Site. Some of these companies may place a cookie on your computer to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. This enables them to understand where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisement and deliver ads that they believe are of interest to you.  We do not control these companies’ use of cookies. 

Some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”), which offers a single location to opt out of their cookies. Please visit the NAI’s website at: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>, (Note: NAI’s website is an independent website not sponsored by or affiliated with AmerisourceBergen). For further information, including other information regarding opting out of advertising cookies, please refer to our Cookie Policy.

**Use of Google Analytics**

To better serve you and other potential customers, AmerisourceBergen has implemented Google Analytics Advertising features such as, but not limited to, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. Using the Google Ad settings, you can opt-out of Google Analytics Advertising.

AmerisourceBergen will not facilitate the merging of Personal Data with non-Personal Data collected through any Google Analytics Advertising features unless we provide you notice of, and obtain your prior affirmative (i.e., opt-in) consent, to that merger.  We and third-party vendors, including Google, may use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on your past visits to our Web Site.

We and third-party vendors, including Google, may use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to report how our ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to your visits to our Web Site.

We may use data from Google’s Interest-based advertising or third-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics primarily to improve our marketing campaigns and this Web Site’s content.

For more details on how AmerisourceBergen uses Google Analytics to collect and process data, please visit Google Privacy and Terms. 

**Use of Google Maps API**

To the extent AmerisourceBergen develops and implements Google Maps API (“Google Maps”) in connection with this Web Site, and such implementation of Google Maps enables AmerisourceBergen to gain access to your information in connection with your use of Google Maps, including Personal Data or non-Personal Data usage information (such as location), AmerisourceBergen will use and retain such information in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

This Privacy Statement constitutes AmerisourceBergen’s notification to you of the type(s) of data that it intends to collect from you or your device when you use Google Maps. AmerisourceBergen’s implementation of Google Maps in connection with this Web Site will not obtain or cache your location in any manner unless we obtain your prior consent, which you may revoke at any time.

If AmerisourceBergen provides Google with geolocation data, that geolocation data will not enable Google to identify you or your unique device identifier.

For more information regarding Google’s privacy policies in connection with Google Maps, please visit Google’s Privacy Statement at <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy>.

To the extent you are located in the European Union, AmerisourceBergen will comply with the [EU User Consent Policy](http://www.google.com/about/company/user-consent-policy.html).

**Marketing**

We may use information we collect for marketing of AmerisourceBergen services and products to you as you interact with websites on the Internet. AmerisourceBergen, or a third party service provider we select, may serve ads according to information we collect during your visits to an AmerisourceBergen website, including this Web Site. AmerisourceBergen will (i) where legally required, only provide you with such information after you have opted in and (ii) provide you the opportunity to opt out if you do not want to receive further marketing-related types of communication from us. You can opt out of these at any time. 

If you don’t want to receive directed ads from a third-party service provider, visit <http://www.youradchoices.com/> (Note: this is an independent website not sponsored by or affiliated with AmerisourceBergen, where you can choose to opt out). 

**Security of Your Information**

We use appropriate technical, administrative and physical safeguards to protect data that pertains to you from loss, misuse or alteration. You acknowledge and agree that no organization can guarantee the absolute security of Personal Data, and any transmission of Personal Data is at your own risk. Although AmerisourceBergen makes a genuine effort to ensure the security of information and transactions conducted on this Web Site, it cannot and does not guarantee communications and transactions conducted online will be secure. You acknowledge this and that system failures may limit your ability to use the online services. You agree to assume all risk and liability arising from your use of AmerisourceBergen’s online services, including the risk posed by any breach in the security of communications and transactions you conduct with AmerisourceBergen online. 

You are solely responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and other security devices and agree AmerisourceBergen will have no obligation with regard to them. You are also entirely responsible for any and all activities that occur under your account and you may not use anyone else’s account at any time without the permission of the account holder. You agree to notify AmerisourceBergen immediately of any unauthorized use of your account or any other breach of security. AmerisourceBergen will not be liable for any loss that you may incur as a result of someone else using your account, either with or without your knowledge. However, you may be held liable for losses incurred by AmerisourceBergen or another party due to someone else using your account or password. AmerisourceBergen reserves the right to terminate accounts for failure to satisfy these terms. 

**Links to Other Sites**

This Privacy Statement applies only to this Web Site and not to third party websites. We may provide links to other websites. We strive to link to third-party websites that meet a high set of standards. However, we cannot guarantee the privacy standards of such third-party websites to which we link or be responsible for the contents of sites other than this Web Site. This Privacy Statement is not intended nor should it be construed to be applicable to any linked, non-AmerisourceBergen site.

**Data Transfer  **

You acknowledge that the Internet is a global environment and your use of the Internet data can involve the collection, processing and transmission of data on an international basis. As described above, we may share your information with third parties and with AmerisourceBergen subsidiaries and affiliates which may be located in, or use technology equipment, products and services located in, countries different to that in which your information is located or stored. Where this is the case, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that your information receives the necessary level of protection and comply with applicable law, including, but not limited to, the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”). 

Any transfer of Personal Data between AmerisourceBergen’s European Union affiliates, subsidiaries and services providers and AmerisourceBergen’s U.S.-based operations (or the operations of its service providers) for processing in the United States is conducted pursuant to established transfer mechanisms such as the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses.  You may contact us using the details below to obtain information regarding the safeguards we use to transfer Personal Data outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”).

By accessing and using our Web Site and communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge and agree that your data may be transferred in accordance with this Data Transfer Section.  

**Protection of Children**

AmerisourceBergen will not knowingly collect, use or disclose Personal Data from a minor under the age of 13, without obtaining prior consent from a person with parental responsibility (parent or guardian). AmerisourceBergen abides by laws protecting the privacy of children. Should a child whom we know to be under 13 provide Personal Data to us, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child to inform him or her that we must have parental consent before receiving information about him or her and then delete it.

**Updating and Accessing Your Information**

To the extent applicable to your use of this Web Site, we encourage you to update the information that you provide to us, such as providing us with a new mailing or e-mail address. This will help us continue to provide information to you that best meets your needs.

In addition, AmerisourceBergen complies with laws and regulations applicable to certain rights that permit access or amendments to your data in our files, including, but not limited to the GDPR. Depending on the jurisdiction in which you live, you may have rights to access, correct, delete, or transfer your information.  Under GDPR, you have the following rights:

  * **Right of access.  **You have a right of access to any Personal Data we hold about you.  You can ask us for a copy of your Personal Data; confirmation as to whether your Personal Data is being used by us; details about how and why it is being used; and details of the safeguards which in place if we transfer your information outside of the United Kingdom or the European Economic Area ("EEA"). 
  * **Right to update your information.**  You have a right to request an update to any of your Personal Data which is out of date or incorrect.
  * **Right delete your information.  **You have a right to ask us to delete any Personal Data which we are holding about you in certain specific circumstances.  You can ask us for further information on these specific circumstances by contacting us using the details below.  
We will pass your request onto other recipients of your Personal Data unless that is impossible or involves disproportionate effort.  You can ask us who the recipients are, using the contact details below.
  * **Right to restrict use of your information:** You have a right to ask us to restrict the way that we process your Personal Data in certain specific circumstances.  You can ask us for further information on these specific circumstances by contacting us using the contact details below.    
We will pass your request onto other recipients of your Personal Data unless that is impossible or involves disproportionate effort.  You can ask us who the recipients are using the contact details below.
  * **Right to stop marketing:** You have a right to ask us to stop using your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes.  If you exercise this right, we will stop using your Personal Data for this purpose.
  * **Right to data portability:** You have a right to ask us to provide your Personal Data to a third-party provider of services.    
This right only applies where we use your Personal Data on the basis of your consent or performance of a contract; and where our use of your information is carried out by automated means.
  * **Right to object.**  You have a right to ask us to consider any valid objections which you have to our use of your Personal Data where we process your Personal Data on the basis of our or another person's legitimate interest.

You may exercise these rights by contacting AmerisourceBergen under the “Contact Us” Section below. In order to protect your data from unauthorized access or alteration by third parties, all requests to update, access, correct, delete, or transfer your information will be subject to verification of the identity of the requesting individual. 

**Contact Us**

If you have any concerns or questions about this Privacy Statement, and the privacy practices set forth herein, including your dealings with this Web Site, please contact us directly as follows:

AmerisourceBergen Corporation

Corporate Headquarters

227 Washington Street

Conshohocken, PA 19428

Phone: 1-800-829-3132

Attention:  Sheila Hawes, Chief Privacy Officer

E-mail: privacy@amerisourcebergen.com

In addition, Umesh Yerram is our designated Data Protection Officer for all regulatory purposes related to GDPR.  The Data Protection Officer and the Chief Privacy Officer may be contacted at privacy@amerisourcebergen.com.     

**Lodging a Complaint**

Depending on the jurisdiction in which you live, if you believe that we are not processing your Personal Data accordance with the requirements set forth in this Privacy Statement or applicable data protection laws (e.g., GDPR), you may have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority regarding this Privacy Statement.

**Modifications and Updates to Privacy Statement**

This Privacy Statement becomes effective on May 25, 2018. AmerisourceBergen may update and modify this Privacy Statement at any time and from time to time, and such updates and modifications will be effective immediately upon posting the updated/modified Privacy Statement. You agree to review this Privacy Statement periodically to be aware of such updates and modifications and your continued access or use of this Web Site after any updates and modifications will be deemed your conclusive acceptance of the updated/modified Privacy Statement. 

© Copyright AmerisourceBergen Corporation – May 2018
